blacklane.com 2019-12-17

# Blacklane

## Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy

  1. Scope
  2. Name and Contact Information of the Controller
  3. Contact Information for the Data Protection Officer
  4. Data Security
  5. Provision of the websites
  6. Cookies, pixels and similar technologies
  7. Special Features for the Blacklane Apps
  8. Social Media / Social Networks
  9. Data Processing During Registered Use of Blacklane Services and Booking Rides
  10. Credit Card Data
  11. Communication with Blacklane
  12. E-mail Advertising, Newsletter
  13. Rights of stakeholders
  14. Automated decisions
  15. Data Erasure and Storage Duration
  16. Amendment or Update of this Privacy Policy

## 1\. Scope

We, Blacklane GmbH (“Blacklane”) take the protection of your personal data seriously and protect your privacy when processing your data in accordance with the applicable data protection regulations.

This Privacy Policy will inform you as a visitor to the Blacklane websites, as the user or the customer of Blacklane’s online platform, a Blacklane app or other Blacklane services (referred to as “Blacklane services”) as to which personal data about you is processed by Blacklane and for what purpose. Blacklane services are not aimed at minors.

The controller for the processing of data within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is:

Blacklane GmbH Feurigstrasse 59 10827 Berlin Germany E-Mail: info@blacklane.com

You can find further information on Blacklane in the Legal Notice: https://www.blacklane.com/en/imprint

Our data protection officer is:

Bernhard Kloos, HK2 Comtection GmbH, Hausvogteiplatz 11 A, 10117 Berlin

You can contact our data protection officer confidentially by mail to the above-mentioned address. Alternatively, you can contact our data protection officer and our data protection crew by e-mail to: datenschutz@blacklane.com

## 4\. Data Security

Blacklane uses appropriate technical and organizational security measures to ensure a level of protection for personal data appropriate to the risk, taking into account the state of the art, implementation costs and the nature, scope, context and purposes of processing as well as the risk of varying likelihood and the degree of risk. The transfer of personal data between your end device and Blacklane is generally carried out in an encrypted form (TLS encryption). You can identify an encrypted connection for example by the lock symbol in the address line of your browser.

If you communicate with us by e-mail, access by third parties cannot be ruled out. In the case of confidential information, Blacklane therefore recommends using the mail or encrypted e-mail communication (PGP). Please let us know if you would like to correspond with us by e-mail in an encrypted form so that we can give you information on the relevant addresses and public keys.

## 5\. Provision of the websites

When visiting Blacklane websites for information purposes, i.e. even without being registered, data is automatically collected regarding the usage through your browser (hereinafter “surf data”). This includes your IP address, the status code, the Blacklane websites visited, date and time of the server request, browser type and browser version, referrer (website visited beforehand), files transferred and data volume. The surf data is stored by Blacklane in so-called log files. If you visit Blacklane websites without having a Blacklane account, we will not know who you are.

We inform you about the cookies and analysis services used by Blacklane in section 6. Otherwise, your surf data will not be provided to third parties.

The processing of surf data is mainly carried out to establish and maintain the technical connection when surfing the internet. This data is also used by Blacklane in a pseudonymized or anonymized form in order to analyze the use of our websites, to design and improve the Blacklane services to meet demand, to recognize and eliminate technical or process-related disruptions and problems and to prevent illegal use of the Blacklane services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks).

Stored log files are erased or anonymized, provided they are no longer required to ensure the general functionality of Blacklane services. Blacklane retains the log files only insofar as you have consented to this or if there are legal retention obligations.

The legal basis for the processing of personal data when providing websites is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest). Insofar as you, as a Blacklane user or customer, have consented to an extended usage of your surf data, the legal basis is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit. a GDPR.

## 6\. Cookies, pixels and similar technologies

Cookies, pixels or similar technologies may be used when using Blacklane services. This is common with most large websites.

Cookies are small text files and pixels are small graphics files, which can be stored on the user’s end device. Comprehensive information on the cookies, pixels and similar technologies used by Blacklane can be found in our Cookies Policy.

When visiting the website, Blacklane will set the required cookies, which are technically necessary, to improve the functionality or make the use of Blacklane services more user-friendly (e.g. language, login status). Blacklane also uses its own cookies, as far as possible in a pseudonymized or anonymized form, in order to analyze and improve the usage of Blacklane services, to detect and remedy interruptions and technical or process-related problems and to prevent illegal usage of Blacklane services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks).

Additionally, Blacklane uses its own cookies, pixels or similar technologies or those from advertising partners (e.g. search engine providers, advertising networks or distribution partners) in order to improve Blacklane services or to measure, evaluate, design and improve advertising measures. Blacklane uses different analysis tools in this regard. The evaluation is carried out in a pseudonymized or anonymized form as far as is possible.

When registering as a user of Blacklane’s services, you agree that we may process, in personalized form, the data collected by means of the cookies, pixels and similar technologies mentioned in the Cookie Policy for the mentioned purposes in connection with your account. This consent may be revoked at any time without any additional costs and with effect for the future.

You may prevent the storage of cookies at any time using your browser settings and delete any cookies present. However, this may mean that some functions of Blacklane’s services may not be available or available only to a limited extent. The storage duration is different depending on the cookie and can be inspected in your browser. The legal basis for the processing of personal data when using cookies, pixels or similar technologies is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a (your consent) and lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest).

## 7\. Special Features for the Blacklane Apps

Blacklane’s apps are another access point to Blacklane services. Similar processing of personal data is generally carried out via the Blacklane apps as via the Blacklane websites.

When using the Blacklane apps, Blacklane may also access additional data in relation to the app or to your end device, such as e.g. the device name, device manufacturer, model, operating system, app or SDK version, mode.

There are also push notifications in the Blacklane apps, i.e. notifications provided by Blacklane in the app of your end device. You will only receive push notifications if you have given your consent to this on your end device. The legal basis for the data processing is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR (your consent).

There is a separate Blacklane app for chauffeur or chauffeur service providers working with Blacklane (“BL Driver”). You can find information on the processing of personal data carried out by means of BL Driver in the BL Driver Privacy Policy.

Blacklane maintains pages on social networks, for example on Twitter, Google (Google+) or Facebook. The respective provider of the social network provides detailed information on what personal data is processed by them and how.

### 8.2 Facebook, Facebook Messenger and Facebook Connect

Blacklane uses services of the social network, Facebook operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ("Facebook"). The controller for the data processing in Europe for Facebook is Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland. Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU. You can access Facebook’s data protection information here: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/

You can contact us and exchange messages with Blacklane via Facebook Messenger.

Blacklane also provides the option of logging in to the Blacklane account using Facebook Connect. In order to do this, you will be sent to a Facebook page where you may log in using your Facebook user information. If you log in to the Blacklane account using Facebook Connect, certain personal data will be transferred by Facebook to Blacklane. Facebook will inform you regarding what data will be transferred, for the purpose of which you may grant or refuse explicit consent. Personal data will not be transferred by Facebook to Blacklane without this consent. Facebook can also determine from your login via Facebook Connect that you have logged in with us and when you have done so. Blacklane uses the data transmitted by Facebook in order to identify you.

If you actively choose to log in via Facebook, you consent to Blacklane processing, in a personalized form, the data transmitted by Facebook to identify you in connection with your account. This consent may be revoked at any time without any additional costs and with effect for the future.

You also have the option at any time to adjust the usage of Facebook Connect and log in to your Blacklane account in another manner.

The legal basis for the processing of personal data when using Facebook Connect is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR (your consent).

We will inform you in our Cookie Policy about Facebook’s cookies, pixels and similar technologies which are used by Blacklane.

## 9\. Data Processing During Registered Use of Blacklane Services and Booking Rides

Blacklane processes the following personal data provided by you when you register and use Blacklane Services or when you book rides (hereinafter “customer data”).

  * Personal master data (form of address, title, first name, last name, company, address, zip code, place, country, password);
  * Contact data (e.g. telephone number, cellphone number, e-mail address);
  * Contract data (e.g. time and manner of registration, status)
  * Ride-related data (e.g. pickup location, destination, times, flight number, special requests).
  * Status (e.g. bonus program), customer history (e.g. previous rides);
  * Contract invoicing (e.g. invoices, status, invoicing address) and payment data (e.g. last 4 digits of the credit card number).

The customer data will be used for Blacklane services, i.e. for the personalized fulfillment of the framework agreement after registration (creation, storage, administration and support of your Blacklane account), for the procurement of booked rides and for the fulfillment of the contract of carriage for the benefit of the customer with the limousine service provider. Blacklane provides customer data to third parties, if necessary, in particular to the limousine service providers so that the customer can be transported in accordance with their booking and the transport can be processed. If the customer has indicated a bonus program supported by Blacklane, the data required in this regard is transmitted to the bonus program provider. The payment data collected is stored via a payment service provider and transferred to the intermediary financial service provider or bank (see Point 10.).

Personal data can be transmitted to limousine service providers in a third party country outside of the European Union or the European Economic Area in which the transport is intended to take place. Blacklane cannot generally provide further information on the data protection level in the third party country. An adequacy decision (see Art. 45 Paragraph 3 GDPR) or suitable guarantees (see Art. 46 GDPR) are not required for the transmission since the transmission is required for the performance of a contract between the data subject and the controller or to carry out pre-contractual measures upon request from the data subject (Art. 49 Paragraph 1 lit b GDPR) or because the transmission is required to enter into or to perform a contract concluded in the interest of the data subject by the controller with another natural or legal person (Art. 49 Paragraph 1 lit c GDPR).

The legal basis for the processing of personal data during registered use of Blacklane services and booking rides is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit b GDPR (contract performance). If the data subject provides additional, voluntary information (e.g. flight number, frequent flyer program, special requests), the legal basis is their consent according to Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR and our legitimate interest according to Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lif f GDPR.

In addition, Blacklane processes customer data in order to analyze, personalize and improve the use of Blacklane services according to the demand, to advertise Blacklane services, to detect, limit and eliminate technical or process-related disruptions and problems, and to prevent illegal use of Blacklane services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks). The legal basis for the processing of personal data is, in this respect, Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest). Data is not forwarded to recipients in this respect, unless it is a Blacklane contractor (see Art. 28 GDPR) or otherwise legally permitted.

## 10\. Credit Card Data

All bookings with Blacklane may be paid by credit card. The credit card information only has to be stored once upon the first booking and is protected against unauthorized access. For this purpose, a certified payment provider is used whose systems meet the applicable security standards, such as for example PCI-DSS (Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard). The credit card data is stored by the contracted PCI DSS-certified payment provider for recurring transactions. The legal basis for the processing is, in this respect, Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit b GDPR (contract performance).

Blacklane itself does not store credit card data or only in abbreviated form for analysis purposes or to prevent fraud. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest).

In order to ensure that the credit card is used by the legitimate owner and to prevent cases of fraud, payment data and credit card information is transferred to one or more external payment security services. This transfer may also include additional personal data. The external payment security services are processing personal data on behalf of Blacklane. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR (legitimate interest of Blacklane).

## 11\. Communication with Blacklane

If you contact Blacklane (e.g. by calling, contact form, Facebook Messenger or e-mail), the data provided by you will be processed to handle your matter and to answer your question. The legal bases are Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR (consent) and Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit b GDPR (contract performance and contract initiation).

Blacklane will also use data from the communication, as far as possible in a pseudonymized or anonymized form, in order to design Blacklane services to be needs-based and to improve them, to detect and remedy interruptions and technical or process-related problems and to prevent illegal usage of Blacklane services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks). The legal basis for the processing of personal data is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest).

## 12\. E-mail Advertising, Newsletter

If you have agreed to receiving advertising or if Blacklane otherwise has the right, we will use your customer data to send you personalized advertising or general newsletters. The following data is mainly affected: Form of address, name, e-mail address. The purpose of the data processing is for Blacklane to inform you regarding current offers and to draw attention to features of Blacklane services.

E-mail advertising and newsletters may contain pixels. In this case, a graphic file is inserted into the e-mail sent in HTML format, based on which a statistical evaluation may be carried out. By using pixels, Blacklane can detect whether and when e-mails have been opened and links contained therein clicked.

The legal base for the data processing is, insofar as you have separately and expressly consented, Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a GDPR (consent) and otherwise Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest) in conjunction with Section 7 Paragraph 3 of the German Act Against Unfair Competition (UWG). Blacklane has the right, in context of legal permission according to Section 7 Paragraph 3 UWG, to use the e-mail address, which you have provided regarding a chargeable booking, to directly advertise its own, similar products or services. If you do not wish to receive advertising from Blacklane for similar products or services, you may at any time revoke the corresponding use of your e-mail address without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs in accordance with the base tariffs. To this end, you can use the unsubscribe link contained in any mail or you can write an e-mail to us using the above-mentioned e-mail addresses (see section 2.).

## 13\. Rights of stakeholders

If your personal data is processed by Blacklane, you are the data subject (Art. 4 No. 1 GDPR). As the data subject, you have the following rights in relation to the personal data affecting you:

The data subject has the right to obtain a confirmation from the controller as to whether personal data is processed; if this is the case, they have a right of information about this personal data and further information on the data processing.

The data subject has the right to obtain from the controller without undue delay the rectification or completion of inaccurate personal data.

The data subject has the right to demand from the controller the erasure of personal data without undue delay and the controller is obliged to erase personal data without undue delay, provided the data is no longer required, the data subject revokes their consent or lodges an objection to the processing, the personal data was processed unlawfully or there is otherwise a ground for erasure within the meaning of Art. 17 GDPR and the controller does not have the right to object to erasure.

The data subject has the right to demand from the controller the restriction of processing when one of the conditions mentioned in Art. 18 GDPR applies, namely the accuracy of the personal data is contested by the data subject or the processing is unlawful and the data subject opposes the erasure of the personal data.

Insofar as the data processing is based on a legitimate interest from our side (Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lif f GDPR) or is direct advertising, the data subject has at any time the right to lodge an objection to the processing of personal data affecting them for the reasons mentioned in Art. 21 GDPR. The controller will then no longer process the personal data, unless they can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject or the processing serves for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

The data subject has the right within the meaning of Art. 20 GDPR to receive the personal data, which they have provided to a controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit this data to another controller without hindrance from the controller to which the personal data has been provided.

Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, every data subject has the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority according to Art. 77 GDPR.

## 14\. Automated decisions

In the case of Blacklane, you are only subject to an automated decision process (see Art. 22 GDPR) in exceptional cases if you re-enter a payment method via which a payment has already previously failed or when current indications justify the suspicion that it is a fraudulent booking. In these cases, your request to book a ride with Blacklane will be refused. Such an automatic decision is required to conclude the contract (Art. 22 Paragraph 2 lit a GDPR). The data subject has the option of contacting us using the mentioned contact data (see section 2) in order to have an explanation or an intervention by a person or to express their point of view.

## 15\. Data Erasure and Storage Duration

We will erase your personal data as soon as the legal basis for its processing lapses. However, legal bases may also exist in parallel or a new one may intervene with the lapsing of a legal basis, such as for example the duty to store determined data to fulfill a legal retention obligation (e.g. according to commercial or tax law).

## 16\. Amendment or Update of this Privacy Policy

Blacklane may update and amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Users of Blacklane services will be informed and may be requested to provide consent again.

Issued: May 25, 2018

Blacklane Cookie Policy

(issued July 06, 2018)

Blacklane uses cookies, pixels or similar technologies (e.g. by means of tags, web beacons or gifs). These are small files which are stored on your end device so that we can recognize you or collect information better when you use Blacklane websites or a Blacklane app.

Cookies may be distinguished according to their operating life between session cookies, which are deleted automatically after ending the browser session or permanent cookies, which are stored beyond the individual browser session and enable subsequent recognition of the end device. A distinction is also made between Blacklane’s own cookies and those of third parties.

You may prevent the storage of cookies at any time using your browser settings or delete any cookies present. However, this may mean that some functions of Blacklane services may not be available or available only to a limited extent. The storage duration is different depending on the cookie and can be inspected in your browser.

The legal basis for the processing of personal data when using cookies, pixels and similar technologies is Art. 6 Paragraph 1 lit a (consent) and lit f GDPR (Blacklane’s legitimate interest).

In the context of your visit, Blacklane will set the required cookies, which are technically necessary, to improve functionality or make the use of Blacklane services more user-friendly. This concerns, for example,

  * Your identification and authentication,
  * Storage and user preferences and settings (e.g. language settings), which you have made,
  * the inclusion of information already provided so that repeated input of information is not necessary,
  * security-related cookies or
  * cookies for using multimedia players

Blacklane also uses its own cookies in order to analyze and improve the usage of Blacklane services, to detect and remedy interruptions and problems of a technical or process-related nature and to prevent illegal usage of Blacklane services (e.g. fraudulent booking, cyberattacks). Evaluations by Blacklane take place in pseudonymized or anonymized form as far as is possible.

Additionally, Blacklane uses its own cookies, pixels or similar technologies or those originating from advertising partners (e.g. search engine providers, advertising networks or distribution partners) in order to improve Blacklane services or to measure, evaluate, design and improve advertising measures. Blacklane uses different analysis tools in this regard. In this respect, an evaluation by Blacklane takes place in pseudonymized or anonymized form as far as is possible.

The following cookies, pixels and similar technologies may be used in the context of Blacklane’s services:

Adjust

Blacklane uses the provider Adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 37A, 10405 Berlin, Germany (“Adjust”).

Adjust provides mobile analytics and attribution services for app providers. As part of these services, Adjust may collect, process and use certain data from the users of these apps (jointly the “end user” or “you”) and at Blacklane’s instruction.

The Adjust SDK and APIs (jointly the “Adjust technology”) may collect and use some of the following data from you as the end user:

Hashed IP address mobile identifiers such as the advertising ID for iOS (IDFA), Google Advertising ID or similar mobile identifiers, Installation and initial opening of an app on your mobile device, Your interaction within an app (e.g. in-app purchases, registration), Information on which adverts you have viewed or clicked.

Adjust uses the collected data to provide mobile analytics and attribution services for their customers and thereby enables Blacklane to track its marketing performance to compare them with their campaigns and to understand how you use the Blacklane app. Adjust also enables Blacklane to track your interactions in their apps in real time in order to see how you behave during your entire time using the app. The collected data is thus used to analyze the performance of marketing campaigns and to provide Blacklane with performance reports. Adjust does not combine the collected data with other data, which would allow Adjust to personally identify you.

You can find more information on Adjust Technology here: https://www.adjust.com/privacy-policy/

If you would like to opt out of the Adjust Technology tracking, please open the following page: https://www.adjust.com/opt-out/, please choose the device you would like to turn off and enter your device identifier. We will then immediately remove the behavior tracking from apps using our technology. If you have any questions regarding this opt-out, please send an e-mail to privacy@adjust.com or legal@adjust.com and Adjust will get back to you as soon as possible. Bing Ads

Blacklane uses the online advertising program, Bing Ads and as part of Bing Ads, Bings Ads Conversion Tracking from the Microsoft Corporation, One Microsoft Way, Redmond, WA 98052-6399, USA (“Microsoft”). Microsoft is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

In the case of Bing Ads, cookies are set on your computer if you access our website via a Microsoft Bing advert. We and Microsoft Bing can thereby recognize that someone has clicked on an advert, was directed to our website and reached a previously-determined conversion page. We only find out the total number of users who have clicked on a Bing advert and were then taken to the conversion page. This tool allows us to determine the effectiveness of our advertisements. According to Microsoft, no personal information concerning the identity of the user is disclosed.

If you would not like to participate in tracking, you may block its usage by deactivating the cookie for conversion tracking in your internet browser in the user settings.

You can find further information concerning Bing Ads and the relevant data processing using the following internet addresses. https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/user-safety-and-privacy-policies https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement

CJ Affiliate by Conversant

Blacklane uses CJ Affiliate by Conversant. Conversant LLC is an affiliate marketing platform which aggregates thousands of affiliates/publishers. It is based at 30699 Russell Ranch Road, Suite 250, Westlake Village, CA 91362, USA (“Conversant”).

Conversant does not collect personal data, unless users provide personal data. In this case, Conversant uses technologies such as cookies, log files, pixel tags or other similar technologies to collect information concerning the browser used by the user or the device used, including browsing activities, online transactions and IP addresses.

Collected (non-personal) data serves for example marketing purposes, e.g. to tailor website content better to user interests. In this case, the following procedure is used:

  * Cookies: Conversant can use cookies to place relevant advertising for the user.
  * Device IDs: Device IDs are identifiers which are assigned by the operating system of the mobile device of the user without disclosing the identity of the corresponding user and serves advertising purposes.
  * Log files: Log files track actions on websites and collect data, such as e.g. IP address, browser type, operating system etc.
  * Web beacons: Web beacons are used to track the browsing behavior of the user.
  * Location data
  * Conversant can assess data concerning the location of the user, while the user uses their mobile end device on which Conversant advertising has been placed.

Conversant can also carry out surveys by placing interactive adverts in which users are asked to enter information such as gender and age range, which can be linked to a device ID or to a cookie ID. When you respond to these surveys, your demographic information will also be linked to a device ID or to a cookie ID.

If the user visits Conversant websites, or responds to an internet advert provided by Conversant, Conversant can e.g. assign a unique identifier to the internet browser used or to the device of the end user via cookies.

Conversant uses cross-device IBA. This means usage of internet browsing, cross mobile application browsing and online purchase data taking place based on non-personal data collection, which is connected to the user, with the aim of adapting user profiles to the requirements of the end user and creating more relevant advertising. Conversant uses non-personal data for IBA for at most 18 months. Aggregated reports generated from this data may be stored for a longer period.

You can deactivate the data collection via IBA by Conversant at http://optout.conversantmedia.com/. Alternatively, you can also use the following link http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/. Please use the following link to deactivate advertising on mobile devices: http://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choices.

You can find additional information in the Conversant privacy policy: https://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy#SCOPE.

Criteo

Blacklane uses the service, Criteo from Criteo SA, 32 Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France (“Criteo”).

If you visit our website, cookies will be used to assign a pseudonymous identifier (ID) to your browser which allows the user to be recognized. With the help of an algorithm, Criteo now analyzes the surf behavior and the pages visited in order to then display targeted product recommendations in the form of personalized ad banners on other websites (so-called publishers). In this case, Criteo does not collect personal data at any time, which allows an identification such as, for example, through names or addresses.

If you do not agree with the storage of cookies, you can prevent this by changing the settings in your browser software or deactivating cookies using the following link: https://www.criteo.com/de/privacy/

You can also find more information on the Criteo data protection provisions at https://www.criteo.com/de/privacy/.

DoubleClick

Blacklane uses DoubleClick by Google, a service from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

DoubleClick by Google uses cookies to present to you adverts that are relevant for you. If you visit our website, a pseudonymous identification number (ID) is assigned to your browser in the form of cookies to verify which adverts were displayed in your browser and which adverts were accessed. The cookies do not contain personal information. The use of the DoubleClick cookies allows Google and its partner websites only to place adverts based on previous visits to our or to other websites on the internet (so-called retargeting). The information generated by the cookies is transferred by Google for evaluation to a server in the USA and stored there. Data is transferred by Google to third parties only based on legal regulations or as part of contract data processing. Google will not combine your data with other data collected by Google.

If you do not agree with the storage of cookies, you can prevent this by changing the settings in your browser software or deactivating DoubleClick cookies using the following link (“opt out”): http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: http://www.google.de/policies/privacy https://www.cookiechoices.org/

Facebook (Custom Audiences and Impressions)

Blacklane uses the service, Facebook Custom Audiences and Facebook Impressions operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ("Facebook"). The controller for the data processing in Europe for Facebook is Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland. Facebook is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

If you visit our websites, you will be recognized via the use of cookies. It therefore can be measured when and how often you return and use Blacklane. Based on this information, we can display advertising to you in a targeted manner via Facebook. The data collected will be stored and processed in the USA. Facebook Impressions allows us to measure how often adverts appear on your screen. We can therefore draw conclusions concerning the effectiveness of our advertising measures.

You can find additional information concerning Facebook’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ https://www.facebook.com/policy.php https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/

If you do not want Facebook to target you with advertising, you can adjust the cookie settings in your browser accordingly.

Formisimo

Blacklane uses the provider, Formisimo Ltd., 32 The Greenhouse, MediaCityUK, Salford, M50 2EQ, United Kingdom (“Formisimo”). Formisimo uses analytical/performance cookies to simplify the usage of the website and to improve our services.

Formisimo does not track or store any personally identifiable information. Formisimo collects aggregated anonymous information and it reports website trends without identifying individual visitors. A visitor is given a unique ID to link them with anonymised data within the application.

Formisimo tracks user behaviour including key presses, mouse clicks and tabbing, but does not track or store any personally identifiable information whatsoever. In detail, Formisimo tracks:

· Behavioural:

  * Clicks
  * Keypresses, categorised as either a correction or not a correction (never the actual keypress value itself)
  * Blurs i.e. movement out of a form field · Forms:
  * Form id and form name
  * URL the form is on
  * Input field names and IDs

Formisimo uses the IP address of a user to determine a country of origin, but the IP address is merely converted into a country and is not stored.

Formisimo also uses a First Party Cookie in order to recognise a user between pages for the tracking of funnels and conversions. The cookie expires after 6 days.

If a Formisimo server or a service provider is located in a country outside of the European Economic Area, data collected by Formisimo may also be stored and processed outside of the European Economic Area. In this case, corresponding data protection measures will be taken.

You can find additional information concerning Formisimo’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: https://www.formisimo.com/privacy-policy https://intercom.help/formisimo/faq/formisimo-and-gdpr

Google AdWords Conversion Tracker

Blacklane uses the online advertising program “Google AdWords” and as part of Google AdWords, the conversion tracking of Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

We use the Google AdWords service to bring attention to our services with the help of adverts (so-called Google AdWords) on external websites. The cookie for conversion tracking is placed when a user clicks on an AdWords advert placed by Google. Cookies are small text files which are stored on your computer system. These cookies generally become invalid after 30 days and do not allow personal identification. If you visited a certain site and if the cookie has not yet expired, we and Google can recognize that you have clicked on the advert and were taken to this site. Every Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Cookies can therefore not be tracked via the websites of AdWords customers. The collected information by use of the conversion cookie serves to generate conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have opted for conversion tracking. The customers find out the total number of users who have clicked on their advert and were taken to a page provided with a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not receive any information by means of which users can be personally identified. The data collected will be stored and processed in the USA.

If you would not like to participate in tracking, you may block its usage by deactivating the Google conversion tracking cookie in your internet browser under user settings. You will then not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: http://www.google.de/policies/privacy https://www.cookiechoices.org/ Google Analytics

Blacklane uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

Google Analytics uses cookies which are stored on your computer and which enable an analysis of your usage of the website. The information generated by the cookie concerning your usage of this website (including the abbreviated IP address) is generally transferred to a Google server in the US and stored there. Blacklane uses Google Analytics exclusively with the extension “_anonymizeIp()” which ensures anonymization of the IP address by abbreviation and excludes direct reference to persons. Using this extension, Google will abbreviate your IP address beforehand within Member States of the European Union or within other signatories to the agreement of the European Economic Area. Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate your usage of the website to compile reports concerning the website activities and to render other services to us, which are associated with the website usage and the internet usage. The IP address transmitted by your browser in the context of Google Analytics is not associated with other Google data.

If you do not agree with the use of Google Analytics, the cookie settings in your browser can be adapted accordingly or the functions deactivated via https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: http://www.google.de/policies/privacy https://www.cookiechoices.org/

Google Dynamic Remarketing

Blacklane uses the service, Google Dynamic Remarketing from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

When you visit our website, an ID in the form of a cookie will be stored on your device, which allows you to be recognized when you access a website which belongs to the Google advertising network. Ad banners may be displayed to you on these websites which relate to previously viewed content. Google does not collect personal data during this process. The data collected will be stored and processed in the USA.

If you do not agree with Remarketing, you can adapt the settings for cookies in your browser or deactivate the function at https://adssettings.google.com/.

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: http://www.google.de/policies/privacy https://www.cookiechoices.org/

Google Firebase

Blacklane uses the platform, Google Firebase from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

Google Firebase is a web app and mobile app development platform which, in addition to development services not relevant to data protection, also provides services relevant to data protection such as analysis tools and interest-based advertising. When you visit our website on a tablet or smartphone, cookies and related technologies are used to enable part of the services provided by Firebase. The data volume primarily results from measured user behaviors on the website and technical data. The data collected will be stored and processed in the US.

If you do not agree with the collection of data by Google Firebase, you can adapt the cookie settings in your browser accordingly.

You can find additional information concerning Google and Firebase data protection provisions using the internet addresses below. The last link includes a table with the explicit data processing measures: http://www.google.de/policies/privacy https://www.cookiechoices.org/ https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy/

Google Fonts

In order to display fonts, Blacklane uses Web Fonts from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which is intended to ensure compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

When you access a website, you browser loads the required web fonts in your browser to correctly display the text and fonts. To this end, your browser connects to Google whereby Google finds out that our websites were accessed via your IP address. Google Fonts are used in the interest of consistent and appealing display of the Blacklane websites. If your browser does not support Google Fonts or Web Fonts, a standard font will be used by your end device.

You can find additional information concerning Google Fonts and Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: https://fonts.google.com/http://www.google.de/policies/privacy Google reCAPTCHA Blacklane uses the service, Google reCAPTCHA from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU. Google reCAPTCHA serves to determine, during the booking process of a ride, whether the booking was made by a human or whether the supposed customer is an improperly used computer (“Bot”). Google makes this distinction using a small test, so-called reCAPTCHA (Completely Automated Public Turing test to tell Computers and Humans Apart). In order to confirm a booking, you must for example check a box or sort images according to a certain rule. It can then be discerned whether the visitor is a computer or a human, Google uses data such as IP address, browser, screen resolution, click behavior and, if necessary, other required data (e.g. cookies). The collected data is transferred to a Google server in the US for processing.

If you do not agree with the storage of cookies, you can adapt the cookie settings in your browser accordingly.

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: http://www.google.de/policies/privacy https://www.cookiechoices.org/

Google Tag Manager

Blacklane uses Google Tag Manager, a tool from Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”) to manage website tags via an interface. Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

Google Tag Manager uses tags. This means that: Cookies are not used and no personal data is collected. Google Tag Manager activates other tags which may, in turn, collect data. However, Google Tag Manager does not access this data.

You can find additional information concerning Google’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: http://www.google.de/policies/privacy https://policies.google.com/technologies/product-privacy?hl=de

Hotjar

Blacklane uses the analysis tool Hotjar from Hotjar Ltd, , Level 2, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta (“Hotjar”).

When you visit our website, in addition to technical master data and cookies, user mouse movements are in particular assessed to create so-called “heat maps”. This information allows Blacklane to design the website to be faster and more customer-friendly. Personal data is hidden in this process and thus not collected separately.

If you do not agree with the approach of Hotjar, the cookie settings in your browser can be adapted accordingly or the functions deactivated via https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out.

You can find additional information concerning Hotjar’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy

LinkedIn Marketing Solutions

Blacklane uses the service LinkedIn Marketing Solutions operated by the LinkedIn Corporation., 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“LinkedIn”). LinkedIn is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

When you visit our website, an ID in the form of a cookie is stored on the device of the user. This ID allows you to be recognized when using the website and collects certain usage data. If you then visit LinkedIn, advertising is displayed to you based on the collected data. The data stored and processed in the USA does not make you identifiable as a person.

If you do not want to participate in tracking, you can deactivate the storage of LinkedIn cookies in your browser setting or via https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out.

You can find additional information concerning LinkedIn’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy? _l=de_ DE

MailChimp

In order to send e-mails, Blacklane uses the e-mail service MailChimp provided by The Rocket Science Group LLC, 675 Ponce de Leon Avenue NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308, USA (“MailChimp”). MailChimp is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

If you register for our newsletter or provide us with your e-mail address as part of registration, the data required for such purpose (e-mail address, language, country) will be transmitted to MailChimp in the USA and stored there. In addition to simply sending e-mails, MailChimp provides different analysis options to inform us of whether, when and where the distributed emails are opened, used or rejected. To this end, MailChimp uses, amongst other things, cookies and similar technologies. If you do not agree with receiving e-mails and newsletters, you can unsubscribe at any time using the “unsubscribe” button which is present in every communication. You may refuse the use of cookies in your browser settings.

You can find additional information concerning MailChimp’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/ https://mailchimp.com/legal/cookies/

Mixpanel

Blacklane uses the services of Mixpanel Inc., 405 Howard Street, Floor 2, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA (“Mixpanel”). Mixpanel is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

Mixpanel uses cookies or similar technologies to automatically collect certain information. The aim of this approach is for example to optimize web services, marketing activities and customer experiences and to filter out the popularity of individual website areas.

Mixpanel also uses pixel tags which are also designated as clear gifs, web beacons or web bugs. In this case, they are small graphic images with a clear identifier, similar to cookies, which are used to track online movements of web users. Unlike cookies, pixel tags are invisibly embedded into websites and also allow Mixpanel to send e-mails and determine whether these e-mails were opened. It is thus intended to ensure that only messages are sent which are of interest to users. Mixpanel does not link any pixel tag information with personal user data.

Additionally, Mixpanel can also record non-personal data (e.g. information concerning the device type used) of the user’s mobile devices when a corresponding application is downloaded.

Mixpanel uses interest-related advertising which can be turned off by users at http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/. The data collection by cookies can be deactivated by adapting your browser’s cookie settings accordingly or at https://mixpanel.com/optout/.

You can find more information in the Mixpanel privacy policy: https://mixpanel.com/legal/privacy-policy/

Optimizely

Blacklane uses the analysis tool, Optimizely from the company, Optimizely Inc., 681 Howard St. Suite 100 I San Francisco, CA 94105, USA (“Optimizely”). Optimizely is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

When you visit the website, data such as cookies and/or device identifiers, IP addresses, interaction times, usage times and language settings are collected to enable in particular an analysis of responses to new features and changes on the website. The data stored and processed in the US is not personal data.

If you do not agree with the approach of Optimizely, the cookie settings in your browser can be adapted accordingly or the functions deactivated via https://www.optimizely.com/de/legal/opt-out/.

You can find additional information concerning Optimizely’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://www.optimizely.com/de/privacy/

Outbrain Pixel / OutBrain Amplify

Blacklane uses the services, Outbrain Pixel and Outbrain Amplify from Outbrain UK Ltd., 5 New Bridge Street, London, EC4V 6JA, UK (“Outbrain”).

When you visit our website, an individual ID in the form of cookies is stored on your device. This ID allows you to be recognized when using the website and collects your usage data. Based on the content accessed by you on this and any Outbrain partner websites, recommendations can now be made to you for additional possible interesting content. Personal data is not stored to do so.

If you do not agree with the approach of Outbrain, the cookie settings in your browser can be adapted accordingly or the functions deactivated via https://www.outbrain.com/legal/#advertising _behavioral_ targeting.

You can find additional information concerning Outbrain’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy

Polyfill

Blacklane uses the service, Polyfill from Financial Times Ltd., One Southwark Bridge Road, London, UK (“Polyfill”).

When you visit our website, data is collected concerning your browser (version etc.), your internet access (IP address) and the URL which uses the services of Polyfill. This data allows Polyfill to detect any discrepancies between your current browser version and the technical condition of our website. In order to still display a seamless and fully functional version of our website via your browser, Polyfill uses so-called “polyfills”, code components, which close the technical gaps and make the website usable. No personal data is collected during this process.

You can find additional information concerning Polyfill’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://polyfill.io/docs/privacy-policy

Rakuten Marketing

Blacklane uses the services of the affiliate network Rakuten Marketing from the company Rakuten Marketing LLC, 215 Park Avenue South 9th Floor, New York, NY 10003, USA (“Rakuten Marketing”).

Rakuten Marketing allows other website operators (“affiliates”) to place a so-called affiliate link on their website which refers to our products and is clearly marked as advertising or as an affiliate link. If a customer comes to our website via such a link and books a ride, the affiliate receives a commission. In order to ensure this, it is necessary for Rakuten Marketing to be able to recognize that the customer accessed the product directly from a certain affiliate which is why the customer must be recognizable. This occurs using cookies which the affiliate places when the link is clicked. When the ride is booked, Rakuten Marketing recognizes that the customer comes from the mentioned affiliate which makes precise assignment and payment possible. During this process, Rakuten Marketing does not collect personal data.

If you do not agree with the storage of cookies, you can change this in your browser settings.

You can find additional information concerning Rakuten Marketing’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://rakutenmarketing.com/de-de/legal-notices/website-privacy-policy

Salesforce

Blacklane uses services from Salesforce.com, Inc., The Landmark at One Market, Suite 300, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA (“Salesforce”). Salesforce is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

You can find additional information in the Salesforce privacy policy: https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/ https://www.salesforce.com/company/disclosure/

SendGrid

For the sending of e-mails, Blacklane uses the e-mail provider, SendGrid from the company SendGrid Inc., 1801 California Street, Suite 500, Denver, CO 80202, USA (“SendGrid”). SendGrid is certified under the Privacy Shield Framework (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

If you provide us with your e-mail address as part of the registration, the data required for such purpose (e-mail address, language, country) will be transmitted to SendGrid in the USA and stored there. In addition to simply sending e-mail, SendGrid provides different analysis options to inform us of whether, when and where the distributed newsletter are opened, used or rejected. To this end, SendGrid uses, amongst other things, cookies and similar technologies.

If you do not agree with receiving e-mails not required for the service, such as e.g. the newsletter, you can unsubscribe at any time using the “unsubscribe” button which is present in every communication. You may refuse the use of cookies in your browser settings.

You can find additional information concerning SendGrid’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy

Twitter Advertising

Blacklane uses the service, Twitter Ads operated by the company, Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA (“Twitter”). Twitter is certified with the Privacy Shield (https://www.privacyshield.gov/), which ensures compliance with the data protection level applicable in the EU.

If you visit our website, an ID in the form of a cookie is stored on your device. This ID allows you to be recognized when using the website and records certain usage data. If you then visit Twitter, advertising is displayed to you based on the data transmitted to the USA. Twitter does not collect any data which makes you identifiable as a person.

If you do not want Twitter to target you with advertising, you can adapt your browser’s cookie settings or deactivate the function at https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads.

You can find additional information concerning Twitter’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://twitter.com/de/privacy

WisePops

Blacklane uses WisePops, SAS based at 49 rue Jean De La Fontaine, 75016 Paris, France (“WisePops”).

Cookies are set by WisePops which store, for example, browser information to ensure the user’s satisfaction in relation to the website structure. The data relates to the last WisePop website visit, the display, click or registration on a corresponding website and further information, such as, e.g., the last purchase date.

This information is not stored on WisePop’s servers or anywhere else. It cannot be accessed by other applications and they are also not used to track you via different websites.

WisePops states that customer e-mail addresses and other personal information entered into corresponding pop-up forms is not shared or sold. WisePops also does not send any e-mails, seeks any other contact with the users for intended purposes or places advertising from third parties on the website. Personal data is only used by webmasters via WisePops to collect personal data via pop-up forms. This information can relate to your e-mail address, your name, your telephone number etc.

If you enter personal data into a pop-up form, we also record your IP address and your country. Cookies simply have to be emptied in order to erase collected data.

You can find additional information in the WisePops data and cookie policy: https://support.wisepops.com/more-info/data-and-cookie-policy

Yahoo Japan

Blacklane uses the online advertising program from Yahoo Japan and the associated conversion tracking from Yahoo Japan Corporation, Kioi Tower, 1-3 Kioicho, Chiyoda-ku,Tokyo 102-8282, Japan (“Yahoo Japan”).

We use the Yahoo Japan service to bring attention to our services with the help of adverts on external websites. The cookie for conversion tracking is set when a user clicks on an advert placed by Yahoo Japan. Cookies are small text files which are stored on your computer system. These cookies generally become invalid after 30 days and do not allow personal identification. If you visited a certain site and if the cookie has not yet expired, we and Yahoo Japan can recognize that you have clicked on the advert and were taken to this site. Every Yahoo Japan advertising customer receives a different cookie. Cookies can therefore not be tracked via the websites of Yahoo Japan advertising customers. The information collected using the conversion cookie serves to generate conversion statistics for Yahoo Japan advertising customers who have opted for conversion tracking. The advertising customers find out the total number of users who have clicked on their advert and were taken to a page provided with a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not receive any information by means of which users can be personally identified.

If you would not like to participate in tracking, you may block its usage by deactivating the Yahoo Japan conversion tracking cookie in your internet browser in the user settings. You will then not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.

You can find additional information concerning Yahoo Japan’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: https://about.yahoo.co.jp/docs/info/terms/privacyguide.html https://about.yahoo.co.jp/docs/info/terms/chapter1.html#cf2nd

Yahoo Japan Remarketing

Blacklane uses the Yahoo Japan Remarketing service from Yahoo Japan Corporation, Kioi Tower, 1-3 Kioicho, Chiyoda-ku,Tokyo 102-8282, Japan (“Yahoo Japan”).

When you visit our website, an ID in the form of a cookie will be stored on your device which allows you to be recognized when you access a website which belongs to the Yahoo Japan advertising network. Ad banners may be displayed on these websites which relate to previously viewed content. Yahoo Japan does not collect personal data during this process.

If you do not agree with Remarketing, you can adapt the settings for cookies in your browser . You can find additional information concerning Yahoo Japan’s data protection provisions using the internet addresses below: https://about.yahoo.co.jp/docs/info/terms/privacyguide.html https://about.yahoo.co.jp/docs/info/terms/chapter1.html#cf2nd

Yandex Metrica

Blacklane uses Yandex Metrica, a website analysis tool from the company, Yandex LLC,16, Leo Tolstoy Street, Moscow, 119021, Russia (“Yandex”).

When you visit our website, Yandex will collect data generated by your behavior. This includes an abbreviated IP address, browser data, click behavior etc. You will also be provided with an ID by cookies which makes you recognizable. The collected data is stored on the Yandex servers in the Russian Federation and processed and made available there for us. According to information from Yandex, no personal data is used. The processed data allows us to improve the website and to design it to be more pleasant for users.

You can find additional information concerning Yandex’s data protection provisions using the internet address below: https://metrica.yandex.com/about/info/privacy-policy
